# ANDREIA FÉLIX **DESIGNER**

I'm a Visual Designer with 12+ years of experience. I worked in different fields, from advertising to corporate brochures, to digital banners and web design but I also enjoy crafting and using my hands instead of computers. I took a break to grow in a very different field (sewing patterns) where I made sewing patterns for the home seamstress and created a website to sell them, I went exploring the world, illustrated a series of children's books, and more recently I started a YouTube channel with crafting tutorials focused on sewing clothes. Now I'm looking for new challenges and for the opportunity to learn new things.





/in/andreiafelix/



https://andriamaria.github.io/

# **EDUCATION**

# 2002-2006

BFA in Visual Design at IADE, "Instituto Superior de Artes Visuais, Design e Marketing" in Lisbon Portugal.

### August 2014

Human-Centered Design: an Introduction (Coursera) University of California, San Diego

#### **July 2015**

Prototyping Interaction (Iversity)

#### Feb-May 2022

Google UX Design Professional (Coursera)

# SOFTWARE SKILLS

Adobe Illustrator
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe InDesign
Adobe Premiere
Microsoft PowerPoint
CSS
HTML
Microsoft Word
Microsoft Excel
JustinMind Prototyper

# **DESIGN SKILLS**

Figma

Branding
Print Design
Vector Design
Logotypes
Layout Design
Presentations
Illustration

Web Design Print Work Book Design Infographics Video Editing UI Design

## LANGUAGES

Portuguese (native) English (full proficiency) Spanish (basic)

# **PASSIONS**











# WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2016-May 2018

MICROSOFT Dublin I Ireland microsoft.com

DIGITAL DESIGNER

At Microsoft, I was part of the UX team working for the Microsoft Store websites (Europe/MEA). I designed banners and DemandGen banners that could be used in third-party websites. I have worked in Back to School, Holiday campaigns such as Black Friday, following the brand guidelines and using internal Microsoft applications apart from the Adobe Creative Suite.

# Sept 2013 - June 2016 ACCENTURE Dublin | I Ireland accenture.com GRAPHIC DESIGNER

At Accenture I was created eCards, eBanners, brochures, posters, Outlook newsletters and merchandising according to the Accenture branding guidelines. I developed PowerPoint presentations for Accenture departments all over the world which are used in customer presentations, bids, and internal events, and I've created infographics for communication and events. I also worked on the Digital team, designing websites and other digital projects like The London Innovation Centre.

May 2012 - Aug 2013

MACIV - Remote - maciv.com

HEAD OF ART

I was responsible for the whole branding and identity creation of the company, as well as catalogues and brochures for customer engagement and stationary for company use. I designed and developed the two main websites of the company. I designed and developed mobile websites specifically for the Brazilian market. I have also designed and helped develop an e-commerce website.

Oct 2011 - Mar 2012

# **EMOTIVE Lisbon I Portugal emotivedesign.pt** GRAPHIC DESIGNER

In Emotive Design I have created the graphic and web layouts for the flying school "ATCentro", I also designed advertising campaigns and developed graphic materials for several real estate agencies in Portugal. I have designed promotional flyers and a stand for the Health Clinic "Fisiotorres" and the campaign layouts for promoting "Sacolinha", a pastries franchise on social networks. I created a marketing campaign proposal and web design for the "Hospital Veterinário da Bicuda" animal hospital image overhaul project. I also developed a proposal for a layout for the dossier "EDP Home Energy", a method for auditing your home energy consumption.

# May 2010 - Jan 2011 CREATION Lisbon I Portugal creation.com.pt GRAPHIC DESIGNER

In Creation I developed graphical work for several brands including ASUS, Petrotec, Adega do Redondo, Ngol, ENI Angola. Gained significant work experience in African markets, namely Angola. The type of work included corporate image, PowerPoint Presentations, image correction, magazine layouts and pagination, promotional comics and other sorts of advertising; products like catalogs, brochures, stationary, wine packages, Christmas cards, calendars, calendar planners and audit report graphics, among others.